Ronald G. Becker Collection of Charles Eisenmann Photographs
Ronald G. Becker collection of Charles Eisenmann photographs
1836-1960
Becker, Ronald G.
12 linear ft.
More than one thousand photographs of 19th century sideshows and circuses, most by photographer Charles Eisenmann or his successor Frank Wendt, the remainder by unknown photographers. Most of the photographs depict the physical abnormalities of humans and animals featured at these shows. Subjects include P.T. Barnum, the P.T. Barnum Firm (Barnum and Bailey Circus), and Tom Thumb. Also included are Becker's research notes, an 1865-1868 run of The New York Clipper (forerunner of Billboard Magazine), and various print (broadsides and posters) and non-print circus memorabilia.
149473
Biographical History
About Charles Eisenmann
Charles Eisenmann was an American photographer. His work, which dates from the Victorian-era "Gilded Age" (1870-1890), focused almost exclusively on the "freaks" of the circuses, sideshows, and living museums of New York's Bowery area. The subject matter was profitable enough to provide a living for both Eisenmann and Frank Wendt, his successor in the business.
Eisenmann was born in Germany in 1850 and emigrated to the United States some time before 1870, settling in New York City. At an early age, Eisenmann established a photography studio in the Bowery. A lower class area that was the hub of popular entertainment, the Bowery was known for its cheap photographic galleries and dime museums. Here Eisenmann discovered his clientele. Dime museums were modeled on P.T. Barnum's American Museum on Broadway which exhibited various human "curiosities" as well as many unusual and questionable "scientific" exhibits. Similar in many respects to the circus sideshows, these museums featured human "freaks" who displayed their odd physiognomies and performed before gawking visitors. To help these performers market themselves, Eisenmann and his successor Frank Wendt supplied them with small photographs that they could sell or distribute to publicists. Precisely why Eisenmann was drawn to and focused on this peculiar clientele is not known, though there was evidently money to be made.
Among Eisenmann's subjects were the famous as well as obscure. They included the "father" of the sideshow, P. T. Barnum, and performers like General Tom Thumb, Jo Jo the Dog-faced Boy, the Wild Men of Borneo, Annie Jones the Bearded Lady, and the Skeleton Man. He also photographed Siamese twins, giants, dwarfs, armless and legless "wonders," albinos, tattoo artists, and even abnormal animals, such as two-headed cows. While many of these "freaks" were genuine, many were not, having been created out of the imagination and costuming talents of sideshow managers.
Eisenmann's career in New York began to decline around 1890, and in 1899 he relocated to Plainfield, New Jersey. Wendt joined Eisenmann during this period, at first becoming his business partner, and then son-in-law. Around this same time the warm-toned albumen print process began to disappear, and to be replaced by the cooler silver gelatin process. The change in process did not favor Eisenmann's techniques. Wendt furthermore lacked Eisenmann's technical skill, resulting in a noticeable drop in the quality of their output by the end of the century.
The images have figured in research on disability studies, dwarfism, microcephaly, albinism, tattooing, "human zoos," obesity, medical history and health, and the culture of amusement in late 19th-century America. Recent publications that have reproduced images in the Becker Collection include the International Center of Photography exhibit "Foreign Body: Photographs and the Prelude to Genetic Modification" (New York, 2002), Charles Martin's White African-American Body (Rutgers University Press, 2002), and Margot Mifflin's Bodies of Subversion: Women and Tattoos (Juno Books, 1997; rev. 2001). A selection of Eisenmann's photos were published in Michael Mitchell's Monsters: Human Freaks in America's Gilded Age: The Photographs of Chas Eisenmann (1979, reissued 2002). Images from the Becker Collection have also been incorporated into Web sites such as the Disability History Museum. A simple Internet search for "Eisenmann photographs" will demonstrate how extensive public interest in his work and unusual genre have become
About the Photographs
The most common method of photography during the 1870s and 1880s was the wet plate albumen process. Albumen prints are characterized by a warm sepia tone that distinguish them from later silver gelatin prints. Eisenmann's images a re noted for particularly being sharp, clear, and well-posed.
The most common formats were cartes de visite and and cabinet cards. These consisted of an albumen print mounted on stiff board with advertising notices printed on the back. Cartes de visites were most popular from about 1860 until 1885, when they began to be replaced by the larger cabinet cards. Both cartes de visites and cabinet cards could be mass produced, were easily affordable, and could be conveniently collected into albums or shared or traded with friends. The advantages of these popular formats helped Eisenmann establish his peculiar niche in the early decades of commercial photography.
The verso of many of Eisenmann's photographs contained his characteristic tagline, "extra inducements to the theatrical profession," which reflected the emphasis he placed on his primary clientele. In addition to photographing his own subjects, Eisenmann also printed negatives shot by other photographers for publications like the New York Clipper. This "copy work" increased later in his career and was commonly performed by his successor, Wendt.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Ronald G. Becker Collection of Charles Eisenmann Photographs includes the work of Eisenmann, Frank Wendt, and others who specialized in creating and marketing photographs of circus sideshow and dime museum performers in New York City during the latter part of the 19th century. It also contains photographs and memorabilia collected by Ronald Becker.
The first four series (Charles Eisenmann photographs, Charles Eisenmann cabinet cards, Charles Eisenmann family photographs, and Charles Eisenmann unidentified photographs) contain photographs and cabinet cards taken or produced by Charles Eisenmann and are self-explanatory. Frank Wendt photographs contains similar photographs taken by Eisenmann's successor, Frank Wendt.
The last two series contain photographs and other material collected by Ronald G. Becker. The Ronald G. Becker collection of miscellaneous circus freak photographs contains photographs of human abnormalities similar to those in the Eisenmann and Wendt series, some of the same individuals. The Ronald G. Becker collection of sideshow memorabilia contains an assortment of correspondence, souvenirs, and printed material including advertisements, booklets, broadsides, clippings, letters, newspapers, pins, postcards, posters, tickets, and more. Among them are a few copies of P.T. Barnum's Greatest Show on Earth Newspaper and some prints by Currier and Ives.
Arrangement of the Collection
Each photograph has a unique identifying number. The inventory below lists them in numeric order by this reference number, with the series divisions noted, although as the reader will notice, the photographs themselves are not always physically in that order.
Other Formats Available
The complete collection of images was digitized in 2004 and is accessible as a digital collection via.
Related Material
An 1865-1868 run of The New York Clipper (forerunner of Billboard Magazine) has been cataloged separately but is shelved with the collection.
Other Related Finding Aids
A detailed inventory of the photographs, including photographer, description, subjects, date, medium(s), condition and size, is available in Excel format.
Subject and Genre Headings
Photography; Barnum, P. T. (Phineas Taylor), 1810-1891.; Becker, Ronald G.; Eisenmann, Charles, 1850-; Jojo the dog faced boy.; Thumb, Tom, 1838-1883.; Wendt, Frank.; P.T. Barnum (Firm); New York clipper.; Abnormalities, Human -- Photographs.; Advertising, Circus.; Amusement parks -- Photographs.; Animals -- Abnormalities -- Photographs.; Broadsides -- 19th century.; Cabinet photographs.; Carte de visite photographs.; Circus -- Collectibles.; Circus animals -- Photographs.; Circus performers -- United States -- Photographs.; Deformities, Artificial -- Photographs.; Dwarfs -- Portraits.; Freak shows -- Photographs.; Giants -- Portraits.; Photography of the grotesque -- United States.; Portrait photography.; Posters -- 19th century.; Printed ephemera.; Conjoined twins -- Portraits.; Advertising fliers.; Albumen prints.; Broadsides (notices); Cabinet photographs.; Cartes-de-visite.; Clippings (information artifacts); Ephemera.; Gelatin silver prints.; Notes (documents); Pamphlets.; Photographs.; Posters.; Salted paper prints.; Photographers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Ronald G. Becker, 1985.
Item 392a, purchase, 2012.
Inventory
- Charles Eisenmann photographs
  - 1 - Jojo, the dog faced boy (Box 1)
  - 2 - Jojo, the dog faced boy (Box 1)
  - 3 - Unidentified man with hairy face (Box 1)
  - 4 - Moses Jerome, elephant boy (Box 1)
  - 5 - ? Man with arms without hands and legs without feet (Box 1)
  - 6 - Charles Tripp, armless wonder (Box 1)
  - 7 - Unidentified skeleton woman (Box 1)
  - 8 - Harvey Wilson human skeleton (Box 1)
  - 9 - Unidentified male human skeleton (Box 1)
  - 10 - Mr. I.W. Sprague human skeleton (Box 1)
  - 11 - Mr. I.W. Sprague human skeleton with wife and children (Box 1)
  - 12 - Mr. I.W. Sprague human skeleton with wife and children, duplicate of #11 (Box 1)
  - 13 - Unidentified lady with very long hair (Box 1)
  - 14 - Anne Jones bearded lady (Box 1)
  - 15 - Anne Jones bearded lady (Box 1)
  - 16 - Unidentified bearded lady, age 23 (Box 1)
  - 17 - Madame Devere bearded lady (Box 1)
  - 18 - Madame Fortune Clofullia bearded lady (Box 1)
  - 19 - Nora Hildebrandt tattooed lady (Box 1)
  - 20 - Nora Hildebrandt tattooed lady (Box 1)
  - 21 - Nora Hildebrandt tattooed lady (Box 1)
  - 22 - Nora Hildebrandt tattooed lady (Box 1)
  - 23 - Unidentified tattooed man (Box 1)
  - 24 - Fred Melbournia Australian tattooed man (Box 1)
  - 25 - Zip, the pinhead (Box 1)
  - 26 - Unidentified African man (Box 1)
  - 27 - Unidentified man with very hairy chest (Box 1)
  - 28 - Unidentified man with very hairy chest, duplicate of #27 (Box 1)
  - 29 - Unidentified man with very hairy arms, chest and legs (Box 1)
  - 30 - Unidentified man with very hairy arms, chest and legs, duplicate of #29 (Box 1)
  - 31 - Unidentified giant lady (Box 1)
  - 32 - Unidentified giant man (Box 1)
  - 33 - Landon Middlecoff giant (Box 1)
  - 34 - Pat O'Brien and wife giants (Box 1)
  - 35 - H. Brunstag giant from Norway (Box 1)
  - 36 - H. Brunstag giant from Norway (Box 1)
  - 37 - Silis Bishop giant (Box 1)
  - 38 - Silis Bishop giant (Box 1)
  - 39 - Unidentified midget woman (Box 1)
  - 40 - Unidentified midget woman (Box 1)
  - 41 - Mrs. Bunnell and child dwarf (Box 1)
  - 42 - Little Jewel midget woman (Box 1)
  - 43 - Sophia Schultz dwarf fat lady (Box 1)
  - 44 - Henriette Moretz midget (Box 1)
  - 45 - Henriette Moretz midget (Box 1)
  - 46 - Rosie Wolf the German Rose Midget (Box 1)
  - 47 - Rosie Wolf midget (Box 1)
  - 48 - Rosie Wolf midget, duplicate of #47 (Box 1)
  - 49 - Rosie Wolf midget (Box 1)
  - 50 - Little Rosie (Wolf) midget (Box 1)
  - 51 - Rosie Wolf midget (Box 1)
  - 52 - Maggie Minott midget (Box 1)
  - 53 - The Adams Sisters midgets (Box 1)
  - 54 - The Adams Sisters midgets (Box 1)
  - 55 - The Adams Sisters midgets, duplicate of #54 (Box 1)
  - 56 - Unidentified midget man (Box 1)
  - 57 - Major Little Finger and wife (Box 1)
  - 58 - Major Atom midget (Box 1)
  - 59 - Major Atom midget (Box 1)
  - 60 - Major Atom and mother (Box 1)
  - 61 - Major Atom and mother (Box 1)
  - 62 - Che Mah Chinese dwarf (Box 1)
  - 63 - Che Mah Chinese dwarf (Box 1)
  - 64 - Che Mah Chinese dwarf (Box 1)
  - 65 - The Murray midgets (Box 1)
  - 66 - The Murray's midgets (Box 1)
  - 67 - Admiral Dot midget (Box 1)
  - 68 - Dudly Foster midget (Box 1)
  - 69 - Major Tot midget (Box 1)
  - 70 - Col. Ruben Steere and wife midgets (Box 1)
  - 71 - Baron Little Finger and Count Rosebud midgets (Box 1)
  - 72 - Baron Little Finger and Count Rosebud midgets (Box 1)
  - 73 - The Wild Men of Borneo midgets (Box 1)
  - 74 - The Wild Men of Borneo midgets (Box 1)
  - 75 - The Wild Men of Borneo midgets (Box 1)
  - 76 - The German midgets (Box 1)
  - 77 - The German midgets (Box 1)
  - 78 - Unidentified man with striped tattoos on face (Box 1)
  - 79 - The St. Benoit twins Siamese twin babies (Box 1)
  - 80 - Group of primitive natives (Box 1)
  - 81 - Fiji Jim and wife (Box 1)
  - 82 - B.A. Bartlett in western clothes (Box 1)
  - 83 - Scotsman with bagpipes (Box 1)
  - 84 - Rose Lesslie fat lady (Box 1)
  - 85 - Rose Lesslie fat lady (Box 1)
  - 86 - Unidentified fat lady (Box 1)
  - 87 - Unidentified fat lady (Box 1)
  - 88 - Madam June fat lady (Box 1)
  - 89 - Unidentified Negro fat lady (Box 1)
  - 90 - Unidentified fat lady (Box 1)
  - 91 - Amelia Hill fat girl (Box 1)
  - 92 - Unidentified fat lady (Box 1)
  - 93 - Unidentified fat lady (Box 1)
  - 94 - Unidentified fat lady (Box 1)
  - 95 - Madam Cortina fat lady (Box 1)
  - 96 - Madam Cortina fat lady (Box 1)
  - 97 - Madam Cortina fat lady (Box 1)
  - 98 - Madam Cortina fat lady (Box 1)
  - 99 - Madam Cortina fat lady (Box 1)
  - 100 - Madam Cortina fat lady (Box 1)
  - 101 - Mme. Carver fat lady (Box 1)
  - 102 - Mme. Carver fat lady (Box 1)
  - 103 - Unidentified fat lady (Box 1)
  - 104 - Unidentified fat lady, same woman as #103 (Box 1)
  - 105 - Blanch Gray fat girl (Box 1)
  - 106 - Blanch Gray fat girl (Box 1)
  - 107 - Blanch Gray fat girl (Box 1)
  - 108 - George James fat man (Box 1)
  - 109 - Unidentified fat man (Box 1)
  - 110 - Unidentified fat boy (Box 1)
  - 111 - Zula Zeleah moss haired girl (Box 1)
  - 112 - Unidentified girl with Afro hair (Box 1)
  - 113 - Zoe Zobedia snake charmer (Box 1)
  - 114 - Miss Zoe Zolena moss haired girl (Box 1)
  - 115 - Miss Zoe Zolena moss haired girl (Box 1)
  - 116 - Miss Zoe Zolena moss haired girl (Box 1)
  - 117 - Unidentified girl with Afro hair (Box 1)
  - 118 - Zoe Meleke Circassian (Box 1)
  - 119 - Illavaro the Egyptian (Box 1)
  - 120 - Illavaro the Egyptian, duplicate of #119 (Box 1)
  - 121 - Illavaro the Egyptian (Box 1)
  - 122 - Unidentified girl with Afro (Box 1)
  - 123 - Unidentified girl with Afro, duplicate of #122 (Box 1)
  - 124 - Unidentified girl with Afro, duplicate of #122 (Box 1)
  - 125 - Unidentified girl with large Afro (Box 1)
  - 126 - Unidentified girl with Afro (Box 1)
  - 127 - Unidentified girl with Afro (Box 1)
  - 128 - Unidentified girl in costume with Afro (Box 1)
  - 129 - Unidentified girl in costume with Afro, duplicate of #128 (Box 1)
  - 130 - Emma Moris albino girl (Box 1)
  - 131 - Emma Moris albino girl (Box 1)
  - 132 - Unidentified albino girl (Box 1)
  - 133 - Anna Mack albino girl (Box 1)
  - 134 - Anna Mack albino girl (Box 1)
  - 135 - Nellie Walker albino girl (Box 1)
  - 136 - Nellie Walker albino girl (Box 1)
  - 137 - Ettie Reynolds albino lady (Box 1)
  - 138 - Ettie Reynolds albino lady (Box 1)
  - 139 - Ettie Reynolds albino lady (Box 1)
  - 140 - Unidentified albino lady (Box 1)
  - 141 - Unidentified albino girl (Box 1)
  - 142 - The Wonderful Albino Family (Box 1)
  - 143 - The Original Eliophobus Family albinos (Box 1)
  - 144 - Unidentified albino man (Box 1)
  - 145 - Unidentified albino man (Box 1)
  - 146 - R.J. Williams boy orator (Box 1)
  - 147 - Unidentified young girl (Box 1)
  - 148 - Unidentified young girl (Box 1)
  - 149 - Unidentified girl (Box 1)
  - 150 - Unidentified young girl (Box 1)
  - 151 - Unidentified woman (Box 1)
  - 152 - Three unidentified children (Box 1)
  - 153 - Unidentified woman in unusual costume (Box 1)
  - 154 - Unidentified woman in unusual costume (Box 1)
  - 155 - Unidentified woman in unusual dress (Box 1)
  - 156 - Stamp photos of P.T. Barnum, Gen. Mite, midget, 7 items, 1" x 1-1/4" (Box 1)
- Charles Eisenmann cabinet cards
  - 157 - Jojo, the dog faced boy (Box 2)
  - 158 - Jojo, the dog faced boy (Box 2)
  - 159 - Jojo, the dog faced boy (Box 2)
  - 160 - Jojo, the dog faced boy (Box 2)
  - 161 - Jojo, the dog faced boy (Box 2)
  - 162 - The Burmese hairy family (Box 2)
  - 163 - Moung Phoset and Mah Phoon the sacred hairy family from Burma (Box 2)
  - 164 - Moung Phoset Burmese hairy man (Box 2)
  - 165 - Unidentified heavily tattooed boy (Box 2)
  - 166 - Unidentified heavily tattooed man (Box 2)
  - 167 - Unidentified heavily tattooed man (Box 2)
  - 168 - Frank Howard American tattooed man (Box 2)
  - 169 - William H. Brooks tattooed man (Box 2)
  - 170 - George Karlavagn tattooed boy (Box 2)
  - 171 - Unidentified tattooed lady (Box 2)
  - 172 - Unidentified tattooed lady (Box 2)
  - 173 - Miss Lulu tattooed princess (Box 2)
  - 174 - Maggie Davis long haired lady (Box 2)
  - 175 - Madam Milo long haired lady (Box 2)
  - 176 - Madam Petty long haired lady (Box 2)
  - 177 - Nellie M. Petty long haired lady (Box 2)
  - 178 - The Sutherland family long haired ladies (Box 2)
  - 179 - Unidentified skeleton lady (Box 2)
  - 180 - Unidentified skeleton man (Box 2)
  - 181 - Unidentified skeleton man and unidentified bald Negro man (Box 2)
  - 182 - Martin Sisters albinos (Box 2)
  - 183 - Miss Martin albino (Box 2)
  - 184 - Miss Martin albino (Box 2)
  - 185 - Unidentified albino girl (Box 2)
  - 186 - Unidentified albino girl, same girl as #185 (Box 2)
  - 187 - Unidentified albino girl (Box 2)
  - 188 - Blind Tom musician 1887 (Box 2)
  - 189 - P.T. Barnum 1886 (Box 2)
  - 190 - Miss Belle Carter side show attraction (Box 2)
  - 191 - Amy Arlington snake charmer (Box 2)
  - 192 - Amy Arlington snake charmer (Box 2)
  - 193 - Amy Arlington snake charmer (Box 2)
  - 194 - Amy Arlington snake charmer (Box 2)
  - 195 - Lulu Lataska snake charmer (Box 2)
  - 196 - Mme. Fortune Clofullia bearded lady (Box 2)
  - 197 - Mme. Fortune Clofullia bearded lady (Box 2)
  - 198 - Mme. Fortune Clofullia bearded lady (Box 2)
  - 199 - Mme. Fortune Clofullia bearded lady (Box 2)
  - 200 - Mme. Fortune Clofullia (Annie Jones) bearded lady (Box 2)
  - 201 - Annie Jones bearded lady (Box 2)
  - 202 - Annie Jones bearded lady (Box 2)
  - 203 - Madam Devere bearded lady (Box 2)
  - 204 - Madam Devere bearded lady (Box 2)
  - 205 - Madam Devere bearded lady (Box 2)
  - 206 - Lavinia Warren (Mrs. Tom Thumb) midget (Box 2)
  - 207 - General Tom Thumb midget (Box 2)
  - 208 - Count Rosebud, Baron Littlefinger, and Minnie Warren midgets (Box 2)
  - 209 - Count Rosebud, Baron Littlefinger, and Minnie Warren midgets, duplicate of #208 (Box 2)
  - 210 - Count Rosebud, Baron Littlefinger, and Minnie Warren midgets (Box 2)
  - 211 - Count Rosebud, Baron Littlefinger, and Minnie Warren midgets (Box 2)
  - 212 - Admiral Dot midget (Box 2)
  - 213 - Admiral Dot, Major Atom midgets (Box 2)
  - 214 - Major Atom midget (Box 2)
  - 215 - Major Atom midget (Box 2)
  - 216 - Major Atom midget (Box 2)
  - 217 - Major Atom midget and unidentified normal size man (Box 2)
  - 218 - Major Atom midget (Box 2)
  - 219 - Major Atom midget (Box 2)
  - 220 - Unidentified midget man and woman (Box 2)
  - 221 - Col. Steere and wife midgets (Box 2)
  - 222 - Lucia Zarate midget and unidentified normal size girl (Box 2)
  - 223 - Lucia Zarate midget and unidentified normal size girl (Box 2)
  - 224 - Princess Lucy midget (Box 2)
  - 225 - General Rickenbeck and Princess Lucy midgets (Box 2)
  - 226 - Henriette Moretz midget (Box 2)
  - 227 - Henriette Moretz midget 1891 (Box 2)
  - 228 - The Murray's midgets and mother (Box 2)
  - 229 - Unidentified midget girl (Box 3)
  - 230 - Rosie Wolff midget (Box 3)
  - 231 - Rosie Wolff midget (Box 3)
  - 232 - Major Ray midget (Box 3)
  - 233 - Major Ray midget (Box 3)
  - 234 - Bertha Carnihan midget (Box 3)
  - 235 - Nora Wren midget (Box 3)
  - 236 - Mr. & Mrs. Louis Weigand midgets (Box 3)
  - 237 - Mr. & Mrs. Louis Weigand midgets (Box 3)
  - 238 - Herman Rice and sister midgets (Box 3)
  - 239 - General Alden and wife midgets (Box 3)
  - 240 - Major Littlefinger and wife midgets (Box 3)
  - 241 - Major Littlefinger and wife midgets, duplicate of #240 (Box 3)
  - 242 - The Wild Men of Borneo midgets (Box 3)
  - 243 - The Wild Men of Borneo midgets and manager (Box 3)
  - 244 - Ashbury Benjamin piebald Negro boy (Box 3)
  - 245 - Unidentified piebald Negro boy (Box 3)
  - 246 - George Williams turtle boy (Box 3)
  - 247 - Big Foot Ann elephantitis feet 1891 (Box 3)
  - 248 - Fanny Mills The Ohio Big Foot Girl (Box 3)
  - 249 - Fred Wilson The Lobster Boy (Box 3)
  - 250 - Unidentified contortionist (Box 3)
  - 251 - Two unidentified one legged men (Box 3)
  - 252 - Barney Baldwin broken neck wonder 1888 (Box 3)
  - 253 - Chinese family (Box 3)
  - 254 - Genuine Hindoo Nautch Dancers (Box 3)
  - 255 - Genuine Sioux Indians (Box 3)
  - 256 - Ella Harper The Camel Girl 1886 (Box 3)
  - 257 - Avery Childs The Frog Boy (Box 3)
  - 258 - Felix Wehrle The Elastic Skin Man (Box 3)
  - 259 - Felix Wehrle The Elastic Skin Man (Box 3)
  - 260 - The Estics Hutty and Tain pinheads (Box 3)
  - 261 - The Estics Hutty and Tain pinheads, duplicate of #260 (Box 3)
  - 262 - The Australian children pinheads (Zip?) (Box 3)
  - 263 - Maximo and Bartola Aztecs of Ancient Mexico (Box 3)
  - 264 - Lady holding deformed infant (Box 3)
  - 265 - Lady holding deformed infant (Box 3)
  - 266 - Photograph of a painting "George Lippert three legged man" (Box 3)
  - 267 - The Tocci Brothers Siamese twins (Box 3)
  - 268 - Millie Christine Siamese twins (Box 3)
  - 269 - Laloo boy with parasitic twin (Box 3)
  - 270 - Ann E. Leak armless wonder 1885 (Box 3)
  - 271 - Charles Adams man without hands (Box 3)
  - 272 - Charles Adams man without hands (Box 3)
  - 273 - Charles B. Tripp armless wonder (Box 3)
  - 274 - Eli Bowen, wife and children (Box 3)
  - 275 - Unidentified man and Scottish outfit (Box 3)
  - 276 - Joseph Jefferson actor (Box 3)
  - 277 - B.A. Bartlett cowboy (Box 3)
  - 278 - Hubert Wilke musician (Box 3)
  - 279 - Hubert Wilke and unidentified woman (Box 3)
  - 280 - Sig Arcaris and Sister Kate, knife throwing act (Box 3)
  - 281 - Sig Arcaris and Sister Kate, knife throwing act, 1890 (Box 3)
  - 282 - George L. Stull wild man, 1891 (Box 3)
  - 283 - Fiji Jim and wife (Box 3)
  - 284 - Unidentified strong man (Box 3)
  - 285 - George R. Kersey giant and unidentified man (Box 3)
  - 286 - Landon Middlecoff giant and unidentified woman (Box 3)
  - 287 - Patrick and Annie O'Brien giants (Box 3)
  - 288 - S. A. Shields and wife giants (Box 3)
  - 289 - S. A. Shields and wife giants and unknown woman (Box 3)
  - 290 - Silas Bishop giant and unknown woman (Box 3)
  - 291 - Captain Smith Cook giant and unidentified man (Box 3)
  - 292 - Captain Smith Cook giant (Box 3)
  - 293 - C. Ureck giant and wife (Box 3)
  - 294 - C. Ureck giant and wife (Box 3)
  - 295 - Col. Ruth Goshen giant and unidentified man (Box 3)
  - 296 - Col. Ruth Goshen giant (Box 3)
  - 297 - Col. Ruth Goshen giant (Box 3)
  - 298 - Col. Ruth Goshen giant (Box 3)
  - 299 - Two unidentified giant men (Box 3)
  - 300 - Four unidentified giant men (Box 3)
  - 301 - Four unidentified giant men, same men as #300 (Box 4)
  - 302 - Four unidentified giant men, same men as #300, 301 (Box 4)
  - 303 - Robinson Brothers giants (Box 4)